{
  "list": [
    { "question": "To address", "answer": "abordar" },
    { "question": "To welcome a resolution", "answer": "Acoger con beneplácito una resolución" },
    { "question": "Verbatim record", "answer": "Acta taquigráfica" },
    {
      "question": "To acknowledge the receipt of a letter of convocation",
      "answer": "Acusar recibo de una convocatoria"
    },
    { "question": "To table a motion", "answer": "Aplazar una moción" },
    { "question": "To second a proposal", "answer": "Apoyar una proposición" },
    { "question": "Approval by acclamation", "answer": "Aprobado por aclamación" },
    { "question": "Carried unanimously", "answer": "Aprobado por unanimidad" },
    { "question": "General meeting", "answer": "Asamblea general" },
    { "question": "Mass meeting", "answer": "Asamblea o reunión magna/popular" },
    { "question": "Advisor to the president", "answer": "Asesor del presidente" },
    { "question": "It was so decided", "answer": "Así queda acordado" },
    { "question": "Lectern", "answer": "Atril" },
    { "question": "Portfolio", "answer": "Cartera" },
    { "question": "to give up one’s turn", "answer": "Ceder la palabra" },
    {
      "question": "To handover the chair to the vice-chairman",
      "answer": "Ceder la presidencia al vicepresidente"
    },
    { "question": "to stick to the agenda", "answer": "Ceñirse al orden del día" },
    { "question": "Selection Committee", "answer": "Comisión de candidaturas/ de proposiciones" },
    { "question": "Steering committee", "answer": "Comisión de dirección" },
    { "question": "Committee of enquiry", "answer": "Comisión de investigación / de encuestas" },
    { "question": "Nominations committee", "answer": "Comisión de nombramientos" },
    { "question": "Hospitality committee", "answer": "Comité de acogida/recepción" },
    { "question": "Liason comité", "answer": "Comité de enlace" },
    { "question": "Credentials committee", "answer": "Comité de verificación de credenciales" },
    { "question": "Rules Committee", "answer": "Comité del reglamento" },
    { "question": "With a right to vote", "answer": "Con derecho a voto" },
    { "question": "In an official capacity", "answer": "Con/de carácter oficial" },
    { "question": "I give the floor to/Turn it over to", "answer": "Concedo la palabra a, doy la palabra a…" },
    { "question": "Fellow citizens", "answer": "Conciudadanos" },
    { "question": "Diplomatic conference", "answer": "Conferencia de plenipotenciarios" },
    { "question": "To entrust a committee with a task", "answer": "Confiar un asunto/tarea al comité" },
    { "question": "Board of Directors", "answer": "Consejo de dirección (directorio)" },
    { "question": "To appear on the agenda", "answer": "Constar en el orden del día" },
    {
      "question": "To convene or summon or call a meeting",
      "answer": "Convocar, congregar con carácter de urgente"
    },
    { "question": "To set up or to establish a committee", "answer": "Crear un comité/comisión" },
    { "question": "To fill a vacancy", "answer": "Cubrir una vacante" },
    { "question": "To overrule", "answer": "Desechar" },
    { "question": "To serve as ambassador to Viena", "answer": "Desempeñarse como embajador en Viena" },
    { "question": "Almighty God", "answer": "Dios Todopoderoso" },
    { "question": "To address a convocation", "answer": "Dirigir / enviar / expedir una convocatoria" },
    { "question": "Inaugural address", "answer": "Discurso de asunción del mando" },
    { "question": "Lecturer ", "answer": "Disertante " },
    { "question": "Working paper", "answer": "Documento de trabajo" },
    { "question": "I call on the representative", "answer": "Doy la palabra" },
    { "question": "To cast a vote", "answer": "Emitir o depositar un voto" },
    { "question": "Between sessions", "answer": "En los intervalos de las sesiones" },
    { "question": "Amendment", "answer": "Enmienda" },
    { "question": "To draw up the program of work", "answer": "Establecer/Fijar el programa de trabajo" },
    { "question": "To call upon states to do something", "answer": "Exhortar a los estados" },
    { "question": "To speak into the microphone", "answer": "Hablar por el micrófono" },
    { "question": "To place on record", "answer": "Hacer constar en actas" },
    { "question": "Sub-paragraph", "answer": "Inciso" },
    { "question": "Final report", "answer": "Informe definitivo (final)" },
    { "question": "Interim report", "answer": "Informe provisional" },
    { "question": "Infringement", "answer": "Infracción / contravención" },
    { "question": "To register at the congress", "answer": "Inscribirse en el congreso" },
    { "question": "Acting Secretary", "answer": "Secretario Interino" },
    { "question": "Head of a delegation", "answer": "Jefe de delegación" },
    { "question": "Swearing-in ceremony", "answer": "Jura / ceremonia de jura" },
    { "question": "President elect", "answer": "Presidente electo" },
    {
      "question": "The assembly will sit as a committee of the whole",
      "answer": "La asamblea va a actuar como comité"
    },
    { "question": "To hold a session", "answer": "Llevar a cabo / celebrar" },
    { "question": "Tenure", "answer": "Mandato" },
    { "question": "Southern", "answer": "Meridional" },
    {
      "question": "I hear no objection, it will be so decided",
      "answer": "No escucho objeciones / Así queda Acordado"
    },
    { "question": "Speakers", "answer": "Oradores" },
    { "question": "Governing body", "answer": "Órgano director" },
    { "question": "Host country", "answer": "País anfitrión" },
    { "question": "To call a speaker to order", "answer": "Pedir a un orador la necesaria moderación" },
    { "question": "Regular session", "answer": "Periódo ordinario de sesiones" },
    { "question": "I ask for the floor", "answer": "Pido la palabra" },
    { "question": "Podium", "answer": "Podio" },
    { "question": "To come into force", "answer": "Poner en vigor" },
    { "question": "to draw up the minutes", "answer": "Preparar, redactar el acta" },
    { "question": "To introduce a draft resolution", "answer": "Presentar un proyecto de resolución" },
    { "question": "To submit a draft resolution", "answer": "Presentar un proyecto de resolución" },
    { "question": "Chairman", "answer": "Presidente" },
    { "question": "to deliver a speech", "answer": "Pronunciar un discurso (alocución)" },
    { "question": "To move (I move that…)", "answer": "Proponer" },
    { "question": "Bill", "answer": "Proyecto de ley" },
    { "question": "Draft resolution", "answer": "Proyecto de resolución" },
    { "question": "May I take it that", "answer": "Puedo/Considerar/Entender" },
    { "question": "Item on the agenda", "answer": "Punto del orden del día" },
    {
      "question": "The motion is adopted/carried by 12 votes to 9 with 2 abstentions",
      "answer": "Queda aprobada la moción por 12 votos a favor, 9 en contra y 2 abstenciones"
    },
    { "question": "Floor", "answer": "Recinto" },
    { "question": "Announcer", "answer": "Relator" },
    { "question": "To refer to the text", "answer": "Remitirse al texto" },
    { "question": "I direct the speaker to discontinue his speech", "answer": "Retiro la palabra al…" },
    { "question": "I withdraw what I said", "answer": "Retiro lo dicho" },
    { "question": "Convention (USA)", "answer": "Reunión, congreso" },
    { "question": "Flipchart", "answer": "Rotafolios" },
    { "question": "The meeting rose at 11:00am", "answer": "Se levanta… la sesión…" },
    {
      "question": "A further addendum to document A/45/544 will be used",
      "answer": "Se publicará una nueva adición al documento A/45/544"
    },
    { "question": "UN Headquarters", "answer": "Sede" },
    { "question": "Madam Chairman", "answer": "Señora Presidente" },
    { "question": "Northern", "answer": "Septentrional" },
    { "question": "To sit on a committee", "answer": "Ser miembro de un comité" },
    { "question": "Opening sitting", "answer": "Sesión de apertura" },
    { "question": "Final sitting", "answer": "Sesión de clausura" },
    { "question": "Official session", "answer": "Sesión oficial" },
    { "question": "Unofficial session", "answer": "Sesión oficiosa / extraoficial" },
    { "question": "Without a right to vote", "answer": "Sin derecho a voto" },
    { "question": "To draw lots", "answer": "Sortear" },
    { "question": "To take the stand", "answer": "Subir al estrado" },
    { "question": "Assistant Secretary", "answer": "Subsecretaria" },
    { "question": "Deletion", "answer": "Supresión" },
    { "question": "Notice-board / Billboard", "answer": "Tablero de anuncios / cartelera" },
    { "question": "Term of office", "answer": "Término, período, plaza, duración del cargo, del mandato" },
    { "question": "The holder of an office", "answer": "Titular de un puesto" },
    { "question": "To take note of a resignation", "answer": "Tomar nota de una dimisión" },
    { "question": "To take part in a vote", "answer": "Tomar parte en la votación" },
    { "question": "Deputy Minister", "answer": "Vice Ministro" },
    { "question": "To resume the chairmanship", "answer": "Volver a ocupar la presidencia" },
    { "question": "Vote by show of hands", "answer": "Votación a mano alzada" },
    { "question": "Vote by yes or no", "answer": "Votación cantada" },
    { "question": "Vote by roll call", "answer": "Votación nominal" },
    { "question": "Secret ballot", "answer": "Votación secreta" },
    { "question": "Keynote speaker", "answer": "Orador invitado/principal" },
    { "question": "Advisor to the President", "answer": "Asesor del presidente" },
    { "question": "Ambassador to Viena", "answer": "Embajador ante Viena" },
    { "question": "Strengthening", "answer": "Fortalecimiento" },
    { "question": "Term", "answer": "Mandato" },
    { "question": "good offices", "answer": "Buenos oficios" },
    { "question": "At home or abroad", "answer": "A nivel nacional o internacional (NOT domestico or abroad)" },
    { "question": "First and foremost", "answer": "Ante todo" },
    { "question": "For good or ill", "answer": "Para bien o para mal" },
    { "question": "Spokesperson", "answer": "Vocero" },
    { "question": "To enshrine", "answer": "Consagrar" },
    { "question": "Chief Justice", "answer": "Presidente de la Corte Suprema" },
    { "question": "Plenary meeting", "answer": "Sesión plenaria" },
    { "question": "Provisions", "answer": "Disposiciones" },
    { "question": "To set out", "answer": "Establecer, disponer" },
    { "question": "To reclaim", "answer": "Reclamar/reivindicar" },
    { "question": "Stakeholders", "answer": "Partes interesadas" },
    { "question": "In consultation with", "answer": "En deliberación con" },
    { "question": "Asesor del presidente", "answer": "Advisor to the president" },
    { "question": "Leniency system", "answer": "Sist. De delación privada" },
    { "question": "On behalf of…", "answer": "En representación de…" },
    { "question": "For my money…", "answer": "En mi opinión…" },
    { "question": "Commend", "answer": "Elogiar / felicitar / encomiar " },
    { "question": "Look down on ", "answer": "Menospreciar" },
    { "question": "Rating agencies", "answer": "Agencias calificadoras de riesgo" },
    { "question": "Businesses", "answer": "Empresas" },
    { "question": "Business", "answer": "Negocios" },
    { "question": "Inequality", "answer": "Desigualdad" },
    { "question": "Add value", "answer": "Agregar valor " },
    { "question": "Commodities", "answer": "Productos básicos" },
    { "question": "Raw Material", "answer": "Materia Prima" },
    { "question": "Per head", "answer": "Per cápita" },
    { "question": "Quick fixes", "answer": "Soluciones rápidas" },
    { "question": "Accession procedure", "answer": "Proceso de incorporación " },
    { "question": "Member States", "answer": "Estados parte/miembros" },
    { "question": "Commitment", "answer": "Compromiso" },
    { "question": "As we celebrate", "answer": "Al celebrar" },
    { "question": "During this general debate", "answer": "En el debate general (NO DURANTE)" },
    { "question": "The people of the UN", "answer": "El pueblo de las Naciones Unidas" },
    { "question": "Peace-keeping operations", "answer": "Operaciones para el mantenimiento de la paz" },
    { "question": "Dwell on ", "answer": "Enfocarse en " },
    { "question": "Emerging–market crisis", "answer": "Crisis de mercado emergente" },
    { "question": "Interwar years", "answer": "Período / Años de entre guerra" },
    { "question": "Trading partner", "answer": "Socio comercial" },
    {
      "question": "Pegged the peso to the dollar",
      "answer": "Equiparó /fijó el peso al dólar o el valor del peso al dólar"
    },
    { "question": "The crunch ", "answer": "La crisis (en contexto económico)" },
    { "question": "Trade pact", "answer": "Pacto comercial" },
    { "question": "Tariffs on imports", "answer": "Aranceles o Impuestos a importaciones" },
    { "question": "My deep appreciation goes to… ", "answer": "Mi más profundo agradecimiento lo dirijo a… " },
    {
      "question": "I am immensely grateful to be joined today by…",
      "answer": "Estoy muy agradecida/o de estar acompañada/o hoy…"
    },
    { "question": "H.E (Her / His Excellency) Mrs. / Mr. /Ms.", "answer": "Su excelencia Sr. / Sra. / Srta. " },
    { "question": "Policies", "answer": "Políticas" },
    { "question": "Livelihood", "answer": "Sustento" },
    { "question": "Languishing", "answer": "Languideciendo / padeciendo / sufriendo" },
    { "question": "Outstanding ", "answer": "Excepcional" },
    { "question": "Confront our problems", "answer": "Enfrentar nuestros problemas" },
    {
      "question": "I hope that we can use this opportunity to…",
      "answer": "Espero que podamos aprovechar esta oportunidad para…"
    },
    { "question": "I have spared no effort to…", "answer": "No he escatimado esfuerzos para…" },
    { "question": "Damage ", "answer": "Perjudicar / menoscabar" },
    { "question": "The rule of law", "answer": "El estado de derecho" },
    { "question": "We are witnessing the rise of extreme nationalism…", "answer": "Auge / Surgimiento" },
    { "question": "Stakeholders", "answer": "Grupos/partes de interés" },
    { "question": "States must be in the driving seat", "answer": "Los estados son quienes deben llevar las riendas" },
    { "question": "Sustainable Development Goals", "answer": "Objetivos del Desarrollo Sostenible" },
    { "question": "The scourge of war", "answer": "El flagelo de la guerra" },
    { "question": "Change the way we do business", "answer": "Cambiar la manera en la que trabajamos" },
    { "question": "To walk the talk", "answer": "Predicar con el ejemplo" },
    { "question": "The next item/business on the agenda", "answer": "El próximo punto del orden del día" },
    { "question": "Key agents", "answer": "Actores / protagonistas / piezas / participantes clave" },
    { "question": "Workforce", "answer": "Población activa" },
    { "question": "Labour", "answer": "Mano de obra" },
    { "question": "Form a large proportion of ", "answer": "Constituye una gran parte de.." },
    { "question": "To shape laws, policies", "answer": "Formular leyes, políticas" },
    { "question": "Developing countries", "answer": "Países en desarrollo" },
    { "question": "Agricultural output", "answer": "Producción agrícola" },
    { "question": "Women farmers", "answer": "Mujeres que se dedican a la agricultura" },
    { "question": "Undernourished", "answer": "Desnutridos" },
    { "question": "To reduce sth. by as much as x%", "answer": "Reducir algo hasta un x%" },
    { "question": "Safety and security", "answer": "Protección y seguridad" },
    {
      "question": "Sth. is in full accord with / is aligned with / is consistent with",
      "answer": "Algo está en línea con…"
    }
  ]
}
